scottishpower.co.uk 2016-04-11

# Privacy Policy - ScottishPower

At ScottishPower, we are committed to protecting your privacy. To understand how your personal data will be treated whilst visiting this web site, please read the following policy. Our policy may change from time to time so please review it periodically.

## Privacy & security

This section explains how we currently manage the personal information you submit to this website, keep it secure and so protect your privacy. 

We’ll let you know about any significant changes to this policy if and when they happen. These will be highlighted both here and in our revised terms and conditions. 

For more general information on how ScottishPower uses your personal data, please refer to [Clause 19 of our standard terms and conditions](https://www.scottishpower.co.uk/pdf/tandc.pdf#page=8). You can also [read more about the use of personal data by credit reference agencies and ourselves](https://www.scottishpower.co.uk/campaigns/dataprotection).

Got a question about anything in this section? Please email dataprotection@scottishpower.com. 

## Your personal information

**How we collect it**

Whenever you apply for our products and/or services, change them or apply for a quote through this website, we collect some personal data about you. We may also collect data from you if you contact us, for example, to report a problem and keep a record of any contact (including by telephone or email) you have with this site. Why? Quite simply to improve the quality of service for customers.

It’s also becoming increasingly important to maintain high quality, accurate data about our customers so that we can guard against unauthorised disclosure of personal details to third parties. 

Whenever we do ask you to provide personal details – and the reason isn’t obvious – we’ll always explain why.

**How we use it**

Your data is used primarily to supply you with the products and/or services you’ve asked for. [A fuller explanation is provided in Clause 19 of our standard terms and conditions](https://www.scottishpower.co.uk/pdf/SPGenTandCv1.pdf). By knowing a little bit about you, we can provide you with more relevant information and so a better service. We therefore research and analyse the information customers provide and how they move around the site on an aggregate basis. 

Based on what we know about you, we and other carefully selected organisations may send you details of offers you may be interested in – unless you have specifically asked us not to. You will have told us one way or the other when you first applied to ScottishPower. 

Don’t worry if you want to change your mind – you can amend your preference at any time simply by visiting the My Details page of the [My Account](https://www.scottishpower.co.uk/account/login/ "Login") section on this website. 

If you told us that you didn’t want to receive details of offers but think that we’re still sending them, please let us know. Just [Contact us](https://www.scottishpower.co.uk/contact.process "Contact Us") with the relevant details.

Saying ‘no’ to details of other products and/or services won’t stop us contacting you altogether, of course. We’ll still need to send you information about the product and/or service you use. What it does mean is that we may not be able to tell you about other products that may be of financial or some other benefit to you. 

**Disclosure**

By providing us with your personal details, you’re agreeing to them being used for the purposes specified in the terms and conditions by companies in the ScottishPower Group and by agents and contractors working on our behalf. 

We won’t disclose your personal data to anyone else, unless we’re required to do so by law to bodies such as the police. Even then, we would only disclose the minimum personal data required, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

 **Who’s responsible**

ScottishPower Energy Retail Limited is the Data Controller for this website. This means that we have ultimate responsibility for the proper management of your personal data. 

Like many businesses, we use data processors outwith ScottishPower to process data on our behalf. You will be 

reassured to hear that wherever your personal data is passed to an external data processor, your information is managed to the same high standard as it is within ScottishPower.

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1988, we only work with data processors that offer security guarantees and we take reasonable measures to ensure their compliance. The data processor is only allowed to process personal data in line with our specific instructions and for no other purpose than it was originally intended.

 **Your rights explained**

You can ask for a description of any personal data we hold about you, what we’re using it for and who has access to it at any time. You’re also entitled to see that personal data.

If you want to exercise those rights, the Data Protection Act 1998 sets out that we can verify your identity (to make sure we’re not supplying personal data to the wrong person) and charge a £10 fee. Once we’ve received this fee and confirmed your identity, we have 40 days in which to respond, although we’re usually quicker than that.

To speed things along, it’s helpful if you can tell us exactly what you require, remembering that personal data consists of any information we hold about you electronically (including emails and recordings of telephone calls), as well as very limited paper files. Asking for all the personal data we hold about you is likely to take longer.

To request personal information, please email dataprotection@scottishpower.com or write to: The Data Protection team, ScottishPower, Section 5, Cathcart Business Park, Spean Street, Glasgow G44 4BE.

You also have the right to ask us to delete or correct any information we hold about you that’s wrong. Even if we don’t accept that it’s inaccurate, we must still make a note of the fact that you’ve disputed certain information.

To request your consumption history for the previous 12 months, to which you are entitled, free of charge, under Ofgem Licence Conditions, please email consumptiondata@scottishpower.com or access your on line account. Your bills will detail all the actual meter readings you have submitted. Alternatively by registering to manage your account online at www.scottishpower.co.uk you will gain access to meter readings as well as other information about your account.

## Links

This website contains links to other sites. Naturally, we’re not responsible for and have no control over those sites. You should therefore refer to their individual privacy policies.

## Security

As you’d expect, we do everything we can to protect your personal data. That’s why, whenever you input your details on this website, you do so via our secure servers. These use what’s known as Secure Socket Layer encryption (high-level 2048 bit) – a leading security standard in the e-commerce industry. The padlock symbol and depending on your browser the Extended Validation green bar is there for your peace of mind. You can also view this security certificate in the file/properties menu.

Most of this website isn’t encrypted, because there’s no need. However, the moment you submit any personal information as part of the quote and apply process or register to manage your account online, you’re directed to secure pages.

Don’t be surprised if you see a warning about non-secure pages while the secure pages are loading within the site. All of the information that’s sent back and to during secure processes goes via secure links – so it’s encrypted, keeping your personal details safe. Here are some of the other things we do to protect your personal data. When making a payment, your bank details are authorised in real time rather than being stored. For added security, the bank details that we do hold (for paying by direct debt) remain partially hidden when you access your online account. This way you can check which account you’re using without letting anyone else see your full bank details, in the unlikely event of unauthorised access to your account.

We also train our staff to protect your personal details and check your identity whenever you contact us. You can do your bit too, of course. Keep your password and account details secure. And always remember to log out of your account and close your browser window when you’ve finished. This helps to ensure that no one else can access your personal data.

## Cookies

To offer you a truly customised web service we need to use cookies. These remind us who you are and enable us to access your account information quickly and easily, leading to a superior, more personalised service. Cookies also help us to gauge the size of our audience and level of repeat usage..

How do cookies work? In a nutshell, cookies are files that we send to your computer, which assign it a unique identification. We can then access these files whenever you visit our website. The cookie is set whenever you register or “log in” and modified whenever you “log out”.

If you want to delete any cookies already on your computer, you will first need to find the file or directory that stores them – please refer to the instructions for your file management software. To stop cookies being stored on your computer in future, please refer to your internet browser’s instructions by clicking ‘Help’ in its menu. Deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies won’t stop our website from working, but it may mean that you won’t be able to access certain areas of our site.

Want to know more about deleting or controlling cookies? Go to [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).
